More research groups have been embodying
our tiny human brain friends into video
games. Yes, the tiny human brains that
you can grow from stem cells and have
run a computer. They can be hooked up to
a chip where their electrical outputs
can be reported and recorded and then
they can send electrical outputs back to
them. In this way, they can be trained.
Some groups have used dopamine as their
reward. That's what Final Spark does.
These guys were the ones who made the
neuro platform. 16 brain organoids
through a chip where they can train and
work together and you can buy a
subscription to use them for
computation. Since the inception of
brain organoids, researchers have found
that they're really good at spatial
information. And that makes sense
because our brains are designed to run a
body in a 3D world, not really so much
for, you know, running calculations.
Those were the guys who embodied them in
a butterfly, which I think is a
philosophical joke. Either way, it's
fascinating. They're quite effective at
it. Biological components like brain
organoids may be a solution to running
fleshy bodies because AI is not good at
soft bodies. This research group tested
their limits by having them play
different roles in a game, a card game.
In fact, they had solo players where one
brain organoid would play player one,
player two, and then there would be a
judge. The organoids had to pick the
highest number card. And yes, they did
get better at it over time. They used
both positive and negative
reinforcement, which is the most
effective. Brain organoids seem to enjoy
ordered signals and seem to be
uncomfortable with disordered signals.
This demonstrated their ability to
understand complex roles and goes beyond
just playing pong. This is also not
spatial information. This is numerical.
Interestingly, they seem to do better in
groups of three, better than groups of
two or one. They are able to work
together in tandem. They're able to
train each other. This is probably why
Final Spark decided to have 16 to a
chip. Now, we know that they can get
quite complex. Cortical labs
demonstrated that the more complex aged
brain organoids were able to perform
better than nent ones. Now, I've talked
about it here. They've been able to keep
them alive for over a year. This is a
problem because you need to figure out
how to get oxygen into those cells so
they don't die. You also have to combat
that with adding things like glucose and
they are just exposed brain tissue. They
don't have a skull or an immune system.
You have an immune system, but if your
brains were exposed to the air, you'd
probably get an infection. This is a
very serious concern for something that
is just sitting there, especially ones
that have been linked up with electrical
components. You have to have some way to
feed them without introducing bacteria.
So, it needs to be an entirely sterile
environment. Now, you might be asking
yourself, where are the ethics involved
here? And there are a lot of different
views there. Researchers have been able
to grow all kinds of different human
organoids, things like skin and lungs.
The idea of the brain seems to be a step
too far. Just about anything can be used
as the computer anyway. I've talked
about slime molds being used as a
computation system as memoristers. You
can use bacteria. You can use rat brain
organoids. So what about human brain
organoids is unethical. They're not
considered conscious for a variety of
reasons. Granted, consciousness as in
the perception of self as separate than
others is an extremely difficult thing
to measure. I think pretty reasonably
they're not conscious. They're arguably
sentient. Should we be using them as
computers given that we can make
artificial brain organoids neural
reservoirs and they act much the same? I
really don't have an answer for you as
to whether or not it's ethical to do
brain organoid computation. It is
fascinating and I really just want to
have a brain organoid operated NPC
buddy. I I know probably unethical. I
just I want it. I I can't tell you